<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-25T14:19:02+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Eman Safavi</title><subtitle>Artistic Technics, Computation &amp; Sound Design</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Elephant in the Room – VCV Rack Patch for InKüle Performance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/performance/vcv%20rack/projects/2025/01/14/The-Elephant-in-the-Room-VCV-Rack-Patch-for-InK%C3%BCle-Performance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Elephant in the Room – VCV Rack Patch for InKüle Performance" /><published>2025-01-14T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-14T11:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/performance/vcv%20rack/projects/2025/01/14/The%20Elephant%20in%20the%20Room%20%E2%80%93%20VCV%20Rack%20Patch%20for%20InK%C3%BCle%20Performance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/performance/vcv%20rack/projects/2025/01/14/The-Elephant-in-the-Room-VCV-Rack-Patch-for-InK%C3%BCle-Performance.html"><![CDATA[<p>On <strong>February 8th, 2025</strong>, as part of UdK’s 50th anniversary celebrations, I’ll be performing with <strong>InKüle</strong> in a special 20-minute piece. My contribution is a <strong>VCV Rack patch</strong> called <strong><em>The Elephant in the Room</em></strong> – you can check it out on <a href="https://patchstorage.com/the-elephant-in-the-room/">Patchstorage</a>.</p>

<h2 id="about-the-patch">About the Patch</h2>
<p>This patch is meant to generate evolving ambient textures and chord swarms in the background. I’m using a <strong>Korg NanoKontrol2</strong> to manage live transitions via faders and knobs:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Mixer Channels</strong>:
    <ol>
      <li>Drone sound</li>
      <li>Chord swarm</li>
      <li>Sequence pluck (with rotary knob control)</li>
      <li>Drum part</li>
      <li>Glitchy high-end texture</li>
    </ol>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Rotary Knobs</strong>:
    <ul>
      <li>Control the probability of Bernoulli gates, which can turn a pluck sequence into a single note.</li>
      <li>Introduce random modulation to delay for <em>churby glitchy</em> sounds.</li>
      <li>Provide a basic DJ filter for final shaping.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>When you open the patch, it will immediately start producing sound as soon as you select the correct output device in <strong>AUDIO 8</strong>.</p>

<h2 id="demonstration-video">Demonstration Video</h2>
<p>Below is a <strong>10-minute YouTube demo</strong> showcasing how I use this patch for ambient/background music. Here, I explore different soundscapes created live with just a NanoKontrol2 and a few simple faders.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CYpGC6zKEW8?si=a8FTnutsvHoV1iOm" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>#vcv #modularsynth #generativemusic #ambient #backgroundmusic</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="https://patchstorage.com/the-elephant-in-the-room" target="_blank">
            <img src="/assets/images/The-elephant-in-the-room.jpg" alt="Elephant in the room patch for vcv rack" style="width:50%" position="center" class="project-image" /> 
</a></p>

<p>In this video, you’ll see the variety of sounds I can shape with minimal controls.</p>

<p>If you want to <strong>support my work</strong>, feel free to visit <a href="https://buymeacoffee.com/emansafavi">Buy Me a Coffee</a>. I truly appreciate any support!</p>

<p>Stay tuned for more updates as the performance date approaches.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Performance" /><category term="VCV Rack" /><category term="Projects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On February 8th, 2025, as part of UdK’s 50th anniversary celebrations, I’ll be performing with InKüle in a special 20-minute piece. My contribution is a VCV Rack patch called The Elephant in the Room – you can check it out on Patchstorage.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Check out my patches</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/vcvrack/2025/01/08/See-my-Patches.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Check out my patches" /><published>2025-01-08T16:09:53+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-08T16:09:53+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/vcvrack/2025/01/08/See%20my%20Patches</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/vcvrack/2025/01/08/See-my-Patches.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="exploring-generative-music-with-vcv-rack">Exploring Generative Music with VCV Rack</h2>
<p>Using <strong>VCV Rack</strong> to push the boundaries of generative music and algorithmic composition. You can access my latest patches and experiments on my <a href="https://patchstorage.com/author/eman-safavi/">Patchstorage</a> profile.</p>

<h3 id="key-features-of-my-patches">Key Features of My Patches</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Generative Music</strong>: Creating evolving soundscapes and patterns.</li>
  <li><strong>Algorithmic Composition</strong>: Using algorithms to generate musical structures.</li>
  <li><strong>MIDI Mapping</strong>: Custom mappings for various MIDI controllers.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="how-to-use-my-patches">How to Use My Patches</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Download</strong>: Get the patches from my <a href="https://patchstorage.com/author/eman-safavi/">Patchstorage</a> profile.</li>
  <li><strong>Load</strong>: Open them in VCV Rack.</li>
  <li><strong>Modify</strong>: Adjust the MIDI mapping if you are not using the same exact MIDI controller as me (which you probably are not).</li>
</ol>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Note</strong>: In case of any questions about the patches, let me know.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><img src="https://patchstorage.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Screenshot-2024-02-03-at-3-65be503f2cf27.39.48%E2%80%AFPM-1024x639.jpg" alt="VCV Rack Screenshot" /></p>

<p>Feel free to experiment and modify the patches to suit your needs. Happy patching!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="VCVrack" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring Generative Music with VCV Rack Using VCV Rack to push the boundaries of generative music and algorithmic composition. You can access my latest patches and experiments on my Patchstorage profile.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">MOOC on Sound</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sound/2025/01/08/MOOC-on-Sound.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MOOC on Sound" /><published>2025-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sound/2025/01/08/MOOC%20on%20Sound</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sound/2025/01/08/MOOC-on-Sound.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-mooc-of-experiment-with-sounds">The MOOC of Experiment with Sounds</h2>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Gaines_(writer)">Charles Gaines</a>: Transcribes manifestos into musical scores.</li>
  <li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anna_Halprin">Anna Halprin</a>: Choreographic scores in modern dance.</li>
  <li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beau_Dick">Beau Dick</a>: Carves masks with their own songs and ceremonies.</li>
  <li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brian_Eno">Brian Eno</a>: Concept of “Discrete Music” in airports.</li>
  <li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scott_Lindroth">Scott Lindroth</a>: Works with The Garage &amp; Found Metal Ensemble.</li>
  <li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christina_Kubisch">Christina Kubisch</a>: Explores the sound of electromagnetic waves.</li>
  <li>Matthew Kenney: Integrates artistic talent and research, focusing on sonification and data visualization.</li>
  <li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alvin_Lucier">Alvin Lucier</a>: “I am sitting in a room” composition.</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.archdaily.com/168979/bernhard-leitner-sound-spaces">Bernhard Leitner</a>: Emphasizes sound as a constructive material for architecture.</li>
  <li><a href="https://design.lsu.edu/student/shea-trahan/">Shea Trahan</a>: Explores resonant forms in architecture using sound vibrations on metal plates.</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.udk-berlin.de/person/thomas-kusitzky/">Thomas Kusitzky</a>: Researches auditory architecture in public spaces.</li>
</ul>

<p>Week 1:</p>

<p>Introductions - basic information</p>

<hr />

<p>Week 2:</p>

<h2 id="i--elements-of-sound">I : Elements of Sound</h2>

<h3 id="notes-on-sound-and-its-social-dimension">Notes on Sound and Its Social Dimension</h3>

<h4 id="the-beginning-of-sound">The Beginning of Sound</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Silent Big Bang:</strong> The origin of the universe, including the Big Bang, was silent due to the rapid movement of particles, preventing the formation of sound.</li>
  <li><em>Richard Rath:</em> Sound historian, author of “How Early America Sounded,” providing insights into the historical significance of sound.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="archaeoacoustics-and-sonic-frequencies">Archaeoacoustics and Sonic Frequencies</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>Archaeoacoustics:</em> The study of sound at archaeological sites.</li>
  <li><em>Example - Chichen Itza:</em> Archaeoacoustics revealing that the sound at the pyramids mimics the call of the Quetzal bird, showcasing how ancient civilizations engineered sound environments.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="tuning-and-harmony-in-sound">Tuning and Harmony in Sound</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>Tuning as Orientation:</em> Tuning not only refers to musical harmony but extends to the resonate frequency of objects and volumetric spaces.</li>
  <li><em>Alvin Lucier’s “I Am Sitting in a Room:”</em> A 1969 performance exploring the resonant frequency of a room through repeated recordings, leading to the disappearance of the original voice.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="silence-as-a-central-component">Silence as a Central Component</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>John Cage’s “Empty Words:”</em> Cage removes silences from Thoreau’s journals, creating abstract language and concrete poetry.</li>
  <li><em>Performance in 1977:</em> Cage’s reading of “Empty Words” in a Milan theater triggers a rebellious audience, resulting in a two-hour recording capturing the evolving riot.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="the-role-of-silence-in-sound-experience">The Role of Silence in Sound Experience</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>John Cage’s Experiment:</em> The avant-garde composer’s staging of “Empty Words” highlights the importance of silence in the experience of sound and language.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Understanding sound involves considering its social dimension, historical significance, tuning, and the role of silence, as highlighted by various artists and musicians.</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Note: This is a concise summary, and for a deeper understanding, further exploration of each point may be necessary.</em></p>

<h3 id="silenced-voices-improvisation--instruments">Silenced Voices, Improvisation &amp; Instruments</h3>

<h4 id="sonny-assus-ellipsis-2012">Sonny Assu’s “Ellipsis” (2012)</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>Copper Records:</em> 136 records cast in copper, with cultural significance in northwest coast indigenous communities.</li>
  <li><em>Golden Record Reference:</em> Draws parallel to the golden record used for interstellar communication; explores the silencing of Chief Biliasu during the Potlatch ban.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="political-dimension-of-silence-in-history">Political Dimension of Silence in History</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>Potlatch Ban:</em> Chief Biliasu’s voice was silenced for 67 years due to the Canadian government’s ban on traditional indigenous ceremonies (Potlatch ban).</li>
  <li><em>Distribution of Recordings:</em> Recordings found through ethnomusicologist Ida Halprin, highlighting the contradiction of legal silence in the community but allowed for scientific purposes.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="improvised-music-and-its-origins">Improvised Music and Its Origins</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>Origins of Improvised Music:</em> Challenging classical notation post-1945; emergence of graphic notation with composers like John Cage.</li>
  <li><em>George Lewis’s Perspectives:</em> Distinguishes Afrological and Eurological origins; improvisation as a form of resistance and redefinition of musical history.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="improvisation-beyond-music">Improvisation Beyond Music</h4>

<h4 id="noise-and-capitalism-and-economic-potential">“Noise and Capitalism” and Economic Potential</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>Mattin’s Exploration:</em> Examining copy left and how improvisation can offer possibilities for alternate economic systems.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="gustavo-artigass-rules-of-the-game-at-the-us-mexico-border">Gustavo Artigas’s “Rules of the Game” at the US-Mexico Border</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>Improvisation at the Border:</em> High school teams play indoor soccer and basketball simultaneously, emphasizing the harmonious nature allowed by flexible rules.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="border-cantos-musical-instruments-from-tragedy">Border Cantos: Musical Instruments from Tragedy</h4>

<h4 id="guillermo-galindos-border-cantos-2013">Guillermo Galindo’s “Border Cantos” (2013)</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>Relics of Border Crossing:</em> Collection of objects from the US-Mexico border used to create musical instruments.</li>
  <li><em>Scores for Border Crossers:</em> Fabric scores, akin to markers for fresh water in the desert, offering hope to those facing hardships.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="global-perspective-on-border-crossing">Global Perspective on Border Crossing</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>Expansion to Global Migration:</em> Instruments made from items found in Greece and Germany, highlighting the global nature of mass migration.</li>
  <li><em>Voicing the Silenced:</em> Galindo’s project aims to provide a voice to those who have been silenced, addressing the largest mass migration in 2017.</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Note: This is a concise summary, and for a deeper understanding, further exploration of each point may be necessary.</em></p>

<h3 id="timbre-rhythm--synchronization">Timbre, Rhythm &amp; Synchronization</h3>

<h4 id="definition-of-timbre">Definition of Timbre</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>Timbre as Sound Quality:</em> Timbre represents the given quality of a sound, such as rough, glassy, or sharp.</li>
  <li><em>Instrumental Example:</em> Different instruments playing the same note exhibit varied timbre, providing a textual quality to the sound.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="timbre-in-cover-versions">Timbre in Cover Versions</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>Evolution in Cover Versions:</em> Timbral changes in cover versions, especially in genres like cumbia, where traditional melodies are replayed with new timbral configurations.</li>
  <li><em>Example - Marta La Reina:</em> Comparison of a classic cumbian melody played on a harpsichord and a reconfigured version using keyboards and synthesizers.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="rhythm-beyond-music">Rhythm: Beyond Music</h4>

<h4 id="expanding-notion-of-rhythm">Expanding Notion of Rhythm</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>Rhythms in Everyday Life:</em> Recognizing rhythms beyond musical contexts, such as the sunrise, sunset, heartbeat, and breathing.</li>
  <li><em>Artistic Example - Seth Kranzler’s “Steve Reich is Calling”:</em> Web-based art using two iPhones playing Steve Reich’s ringtone with slightly different tempos, creating a rhythmically abundant experience.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="mayan-counting-systems-and-rhythm">Mayan Counting Systems and Rhythm</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>Mayan Acoustic Systems:</em> Mayan counting system includes acoustic or soundic elements, with dots and claps representing numbers, creating complex rhythms and calculations.</li>
  <li><em>Pedro’s Insight:</em> Highlighting the acoustic aspect of Mayan numbers often overlooked in scholarship.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="synchronization-in-djing">Synchronization in DJing</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>DJ Synchronization:</em> Basic explanation of synchronization in music, focusing on DJs aligning songs with the same tempo.</li>
  <li><em>Creation of a Third Song:</em> DJs synchronize songs to create a seamless blend and transition, utilizing time as the art medium.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="conclusion-1">Conclusion</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Understanding the elements of timbre and rhythm enhances our appreciation of sound in both musical and everyday life contexts.</li>
  <li>Artists creatively manipulate these elements to evoke different emotions and experiences, showcasing the versatility and richness of sound.</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Note: This is a concise summary, and for a deeper understanding, further exploration of each point may be necessary.</em></p>

<h3 id="duration-streaming--the-studio-as-instrument">Duration, Streaming &amp; the Studio as Instrument</h3>

<h4 id="introduction-to-duration-in-contemporary-art">Introduction to Duration in Contemporary Art</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>Importance of Duration:</em> Duration is a crucial concept, especially in socially engaged art, challenging the framed and temporal nature of traditional art experiences.</li>
  <li><em>Focus on Everyday Life:</em> Artists use extended durations to blur the boundaries between art and everyday life, prompting contemplation on the continuous flow of life.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="dream-house-a-sonic-installation">Dream House: A Sonic Installation</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>La Monte Young and Marian Zazeela:</em> In 1979, artists created “Dream House,” a sound and light installation with oscillators and synthesizers, challenging conventional ideas of sound and music.</li>
  <li><em>Unique Characteristics:</em> The piece challenges the traditional commercial aspects of music, as it has been running since the late ’70s, questioning the need for change and commercialization in music.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="duration-in-the-digital-age">Duration in the Digital Age</h4>

<h4 id="territorialized-experiences-of-duration">Territorialized Experiences of Duration</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>Streaming and Duration:</em> Introduction of new technologies like streaming has transformed the experience of duration, offering a digital superabundance but challenging traditional notions of plotting and narrative.</li>
  <li><em>Streaming Conflicts:</em> Conflict arises between the accessibility of streaming and the loss of original context, as streaming often provides limited information compared to physical media.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="evolution-of-sampling-and-studio-as-an-instrument">Evolution of Sampling and Studio as an Instrument</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>Sampling as Craft:</em> Sampling, once a manual craft, has evolved with digital technology, allowing easy copy-paste functions.</li>
  <li><em>Studio as an Instrument:</em> The notion of the studio as a musical instrument strengthened in the golden era of Jamaican recording studios, exemplified by artists like King Tubby and Lee Scratch Perry.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="auto-tune-from-corrective-to-creative">Auto-Tune: From Corrective to Creative</h4>

<ul>
  <li><em>Auto-Tune’s Invention:</em> Initially invented for corrective purposes in 1997, Auto-Tune gained creative applications, notably in Cher’s song “Believe.”</li>
  <li><em>Extreme Examples:</em> Auto-Tune extremes illustrated through corrective use in Billy Joel’s Super Bowl performance and creative application in Berber, Moroccan weddings.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="conclusion-2">Conclusion</h4>

<ul>
  <li>The exploration of duration in art spans sonic installations, digital transformations, and the evolution of studio practices.
    <h2 id="christopher-delaurenti-the-sonic-explorer">Christopher DeLaurenti: The Sonic Explorer</h2>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="introduction">Introduction</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Introduction:</strong> The speaker warmly welcomes Christopher DeLaurenti, a distinguished guest presenter known for dedicating most of his life to the world of sound.</li>
  <li><strong>Versatile Practice:</strong> Christopher’s diverse productions span found soundscapes, installation art, traditional phonography, electroacoustic and chamber music compositions, improvisation, and score production.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="journey-into-sound">Journey into Sound</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Early Influences:</strong> Christopher’s journey into sound began as a listener, influenced by his poor eyesight, which led him to navigate the world through listening and squinting.</li>
  <li><strong>Musical Heritage:</strong> Growing up in a family of musicians, especially with his father’s multi-decade career, surrounded Christopher with music, shaping his perspective on art and the importance of listening.</li>
  <li><strong>Teenage Rebellion:</strong> Initially intending to become an anthropologist, Christopher rebelled against his musical upbringing as a teenager. However, he inherited a diverse collection of acoustic instruments and recording equipment, sparking his exploration of creating an orchestra from salvaged instruments.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="evolution-through-field-recording">Evolution through Field Recording</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Field Recording Origin:</strong> Christopher’s venture into field recording started by taking microphones outside the studio, capturing sounds not typically associated with traditional recording.</li>
  <li><strong>Political Awakening:</strong> The pivotal moment occurred during the WTO protests in Seattle on November 30th, 1999, where Christopher recorded the protests, leading to a deep political and artistic awakening.</li>
  <li><strong>Soundscape Concept:</strong> Inspired by R. Murray Schafer’s “Tuning of the World,” Christopher realized the political significance of soundscapes, embodying a soniferous garden that binds people through shared sounds.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="artistic-choices-and-philosophy">Artistic Choices and Philosophy</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Absence of Names:</strong> Christopher’s work often lacks names, focusing on the essence of what people say rather than individual identities.</li>
  <li><strong>Is it Alive?:</strong> Guided by the question “Is the sound alive?” Christopher discerns the authenticity and humanity in sounds, creating works that feel real and resonate with listeners.</li>
  <li><strong>Diverse Mediums:</strong> While primarily focused on phonography and field recording, Christopher embraces various mediums, including live performances, installations, and videos, all centered around the core question of the gig being about listening.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="unique-instruments">Unique Instruments</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>The Flap-O-Phone:</strong> A cardboard record player crafted from salvaged materials, the Flap-O-Phone invites a unique way of playing records, emphasizing the acoustic nature of the instrument.</li>
  <li><strong>Experimental Performances:</strong> Christopher explores unconventional performance spaces, including busking on street corners, engaging people’s curiosity and inviting them to play the Flap-O-Phone.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="exploration-of-glenn-goulds-work">Exploration of Glenn Gould’s Work</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Obsession with Glenn Gould:</strong> Christopher shares a 20-year obsession with Glenn Gould’s radiophonic piece, “The Idea of North,” exploring its monaural format and contrapuntal radio concept.</li>
  <li><strong>Soundscape of Descent:</strong> Gould’s work inspires Christopher to understand it as a soundscape of descent, exploring humanity’s impact on territories and the search for meaning in moments of silence and acoustic curtains.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="conclusion-3">Conclusion</h3>

<p>Christopher DeLaurenti’s sonic exploration delves into the depths of sound, weaving together elements of personal history, political awakening, and a commitment to listening. His diverse artistic expressions, from field recording to experimental instruments, highlight the transformative power of sound in capturing and conveying the essence of human experience.</p>
<h2 id="guest-presentations">Guest Presentations</h2>

<h3 id="the-garage--found-metal-ensemble-with-scott-lindroth">The Garage &amp; Found Metal Ensemble with Scott Lindroth</h3>

<h4 id="background-and-motivation">Background and Motivation</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Versatility in Compositions:</strong> Scott has a rich history in both traditional music compositions and innovative works that delve into spatial dynamics, assemblies, and social interactions.</li>
  <li><strong>Interactive Environments:</strong> The discussion opens with mention of Scott’s project at the Museum of Life and Science, involving a motion-sensitive environment for people of all ages to engage with.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="current-project-mechanical-ensemble">Current Project: Mechanical Ensemble</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Found Object Ensemble:</strong> Scott introduces a current project, showcasing a mechanical ensemble crafted from miscellaneous scrap metal collected from a local recycling center.</li>
  <li><strong>Balancing Digital and Physical Presence:</strong> The goal is to integrate digital media while preserving the physicality of performance. Scott aims to bring a tangible presence of instruments to the stage, juxtaposed with digital processing.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="evolution-of-the-project">Evolution of the Project</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Live Performers in Future Iterations:</strong> While the current iteration lacks live performers, Scott envisions incorporating them in the future. The mechanical ensemble serves as a backdrop, with an algorithm simulating the gradual synchronization of instruments, inspired by biological synchrony like flashing fireflies.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="working-with-found-objects">Working with Found Objects</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Humble Materials:</strong> Scott discusses the use of humble materials, drawing parallels with an earlier piece involving solo percussion with electronics and found objects. The current project expands on this concept, incorporating a variety of scrap metal tuned to specific scales.</li>
  <li><strong>Temporary Nature:</strong> Embracing the provisional and temporary nature of the ensemble, Scott appreciates the impermanence of the instruments, each with its unique purpose and eventual discard.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="birthplace-the-garage">Birthplace: The Garage</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Liberatory Setting:</strong> The project originated in Scott’s garage, offering a liberatory environment distinct from traditional concert spaces.</li>
  <li><strong>Different Experiences:</strong> The garage setting promotes a unique way of experiencing sound and music, fostering interaction and constant tinkering to enhance the ensemble’s performance.</li>
  <li><strong>Cognitive Dissonance:</strong> The resulting sound creates a cognitive dissonance, making the space seem larger and more elaborate than its natural habitat, adding to the project’s appeal.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="continuous-iteration-and-enhancement">Continuous Iteration and Enhancement</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Ongoing Development:</strong> Scott emphasizes the continuous interaction with the ensemble, striving to enhance its functionality and sonic output.</li>
  <li><strong>Cognitive Dissonance:</strong> The project’s ability to create an expansive sonic experience in a seemingly modest space adds an intriguing dimension to the overall artistic impact.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="the-sound-of-electromagnetic-waves-with-christina-kubisch">The Sound of Electromagnetic Waves with Christina Kubisch</h3>

<h4 id="perception-of-acoustic-environments">Perception of Acoustic Environments</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Definition:</strong> Acoustic environments are described as encompassing both audible and hidden sounds, ranging from daily life occurrences to the concealed auditory world waiting to be discovered.</li>
  <li><strong>Variety of Perspectives:</strong> The perception of acoustic environments is acknowledged to vary based on physiological, scientific, or artistic viewpoints.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="journey-into-electroacoustic-exploration">Journey into Electroacoustic Exploration</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Educational Background:</strong> Kubisch shares her transition from studying traditional composition in flute to exploring electroacoustic music in Milan.</li>
  <li><strong>Shift in Focus:</strong> Dissatisfied with the technical emphasis of electroacoustic courses, Kubisch turned to evening courses at the Technical University, discovering a new world that allowed her to translate her artistic ideas.</li>
  <li><strong>Chance Discovery:</strong> The accidental sound emanating from a telephone amplifier in her handbag sparked Kubisch’s fascination with electromagnetic fields, leading to a journey of investigation.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="electromagnetic-exploration-and-composition">Electromagnetic Exploration and Composition</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Innovative Approach:</strong> Kubisch’s exploration involved using unconventional means, such as electromagnetic fields and telephone amplifiers, to create a unique auditory experience.</li>
  <li><strong>Materialization of Imprints:</strong> She shares her experiments with magnetic induction, utilizing thick electrical cables to form loops that served as visual and auditory material for composition.</li>
  <li><strong>Evolution to Headphones:</strong> The transition from cubes to headphones aimed at improving reception while retaining the core elements of coils, translation, and insulation.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="chatter-sounds-and-urban-exploration">Chatter Sounds and Urban Exploration</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Shift in Soundscape:</strong> Kubisch reflects on the changing auditory landscape, noting a surge in electromagnetic waves in the ’90s that couldn’t be filtered or avoided.</li>
  <li><strong>Adaptation:</strong> Faced with the increase in “chatter sounds,” Kubisch adapted her approach, constructing open headphones to capture the entirety of the surrounding environment.</li>
  <li><strong>Urban Soundscape Exploration:</strong> She delves into listening to various cities, finding the cacophony of urban chatter sounds to be a fascinating and messy tapestry.</li>
</ul>

<p>Christina Kubisch’s journey unfolds as a dynamic intersection of art, science, and the evolving acoustic world she navigates with curiosity and creativity.</p>

<h3 id="materializing--sonification-of-movement-with-matthew-kenney">Materializing &amp; Sonification of Movement with Matthew Kenney</h3>

<h4 id="integration-of-artistic-talent-and-research">Integration of Artistic Talent and Research</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Artistic Devotion:</strong> Matt’s artistic journey involves not only creativity but also a profound dedication to transforming vast datasets into tangible physical entities.</li>
  <li><strong>Inspirations from Composition:</strong> Influenced by avant-garde composers like Iannis Xenakis and John Cage, Matt initially explored algorithms to drive his work, emphasizing generative pieces and experimental structures.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="algorithmic-experimentation">Algorithmic Experimentation</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Iterative Process:</strong> In the early stages, Matt engaged in algorithmic experimentation, throwing nodes or voids into a space and iteratively stopping when intriguing or striking physical structures emerged.</li>
  <li><strong>Focus on Structure:</strong> The emphasis was on using algorithms to drive and shape the physical structures, initially in experimental architecture and form-making.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="sonification-and-data-visualization">Sonification and Data Visualization</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Concept-Driven Approach:</strong> Transitioning to sonification and data visualization, Matt delved into the conceptual core and meat of the data to create pieces with meaningful and impactful auditory and visual experiences.</li>
  <li><strong>Example: Antarctic Ice Melt Data:</strong> He discusses a sonification project based on 400,000 years of Antarctic ice melt data, where the challenge was to condense the time scale while maintaining an enjoyable listening experience.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="3d-printing-with-clay">3D Printing with Clay</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Hurricane Data Project:</strong> Matt shares a project involving 3D printing with clay, translating hurricane data into tangible clay works. The collaboration aimed to capture wind speed and the movement of hurricanes, merging technology with physicality.</li>
  <li><strong>Public Dimension:</strong> The project involved a public dimension, with the clay prints becoming part of a larger display in Venice, connecting data to a physical and public art context.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="biomechanics-lab-collaboration">Biomechanics Lab Collaboration</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Chicks on Speed Collaboration:</strong> Matt collaborated with Chicks on Speed, integrating sensors to track movements in real-time, transforming the data into sonifications using programs like supercollider.</li>
  <li><strong>Public Performance:</strong> The sonifications added another layer to a public performance in Venice, blending the abstract and athletic movements of the artist with the main performance.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="unique-physicality-in-art">Unique Physicality in Art</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Capturing Abstract Movements:</strong> The collaboration with Chicks on Speed allowed Matt to capture abstract yet physical and athletic movements, introducing a unique physicality to the project through sonification.</li>
  <li><strong>Intersection with Dance:</strong> The project, documented in performance, connects with more traditional approaches to art, particularly in dance, bringing a distinct set of movements into the artistic practice.</li>
</ul>

<p>Matt’s exploration exemplifies the powerful intersection of data, art, and physical manifestation, pushing the boundaries of artistic expression through innovative approaches to composition and visualization.</p>

<h3 id="auditory-architecture-with-thomas-kusitzky">Auditory Architecture with Thomas Kusitzky</h3>

<h4 id="perception-of-acoustic-environments-1">Perception of Acoustic Environments</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Definition:</strong> Acoustic environments are described as encompassing both audible and hidden sounds, ranging from daily life occurrences to the concealed auditory world waiting to be discovered.</li>
  <li><strong>Variety of Perspectives:</strong> The perception of acoustic environments is acknowledged to vary based on physiological, scientific, or artistic viewpoints.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="journey-into-electroacoustic-exploration-1">Journey into Electroacoustic Exploration</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Educational Background:</strong> Kubisch shares her transition from studying traditional composition in flute to exploring electroacoustic music in Milan.</li>
  <li><strong>Shift in Focus:</strong> Dissatisfied with the technical emphasis of electroacoustic courses, Kubisch turned to evening courses at the Technical University, discovering a new world that allowed her to translate her artistic ideas.</li>
  <li><strong>Chance Discovery:</strong> The accidental sound emanating from a telephone amplifier in her handbag sparked Kubisch’s fascination with electromagnetic fields, leading to a journey of investigation.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="electromagnetic-exploration-and-composition-1">Electromagnetic Exploration and Composition</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Innovative Approach:</strong> Kubisch’s exploration involved using unconventional means, such as electromagnetic fields and telephone amplifiers, to create a unique auditory experience.</li>
  <li><strong>Materialization of Imprints:</strong> She shares her experiments with magnetic induction, utilizing thick electrical cables to form loops that served as visual and auditory material for composition.</li>
  <li><strong>Evolution to Headphones:</strong> The transition from cubes to headphones aimed at improving reception while retaining the core elements of coils, translation, and insulation.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="chatter-sounds-and-urban-exploration-1">Chatter Sounds and Urban Exploration</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Shift in Soundscape:</strong> Kubisch reflects on the changing auditory landscape, noting a surge in electromagnetic waves in the ’90s that couldn’t be filtered or avoided.</li>
  <li><strong>Adaptation:</strong> Faced with the increase in “chatter sounds,” Kubisch adapted her approach, constructing open headphones to capture the entirety of the surrounding environment.</li>
  <li><strong>Urban Soundscape Exploration:</strong> She delves into listening to various cities, finding the cacophony of urban chatter sounds to be a fascinating and messy tapestry.</li>
</ul>

<p>Christina Kubisch’s journey unfolds as a dynamic intersection of art, science, and the evolving acoustic world she navigates with curiosity and creativity.</p>

<p>Week 5:</p>

<p>Assignment</p>

<hr />

<p>Week 6:</p>

<h2 id="iii--sound-and-technology">III : Sound and Technology</h2>

<h3 id="introduction-to-sound-and-technology">Introduction to Sound and Technology</h3>

<h4 id="overview">Overview</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Theme of the Week:</strong> This week’s lectures focus on the intersection of sound and technology, exploring how technological advancements have influenced the creation, manipulation, and perception of sound.</li>
  <li><strong>Historical Context:</strong> The discussion begins with a historical overview of technological innovations in sound, from early mechanical instruments to modern digital tools.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="early-mechanical-instruments">Early Mechanical Instruments</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Phonograph and Gramophone:</strong> The invention of the phonograph by Thomas Edison and the gramophone by Emile Berliner revolutionized the way sound was recorded and played back, marking the beginning of the sound recording industry.</li>
  <li><strong>Mechanical Music Boxes:</strong> Mechanical music boxes, with their intricate mechanisms, provided early examples of automated sound production, influencing later developments in electronic music.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="analog-to-digital-transition">Analog to Digital Transition</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Analog Recording:</strong> The transition from mechanical to analog recording introduced magnetic tape, allowing for higher fidelity and more flexible editing capabilities.</li>
  <li><strong>Digital Revolution:</strong> The advent of digital technology transformed sound recording and manipulation, with digital audio workstations (DAWs) becoming essential tools for musicians and sound engineers.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="modern-digital-tools">Modern Digital Tools</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Software and Plugins:</strong> Modern digital tools, including software and plugins, offer unprecedented control over sound manipulation, enabling complex effects and precise editing.</li>
  <li><strong>Virtual Instruments:</strong> Virtual instruments simulate traditional instruments and create entirely new sounds, expanding the possibilities for composers and producers.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="sound-synthesis-and-sampling">Sound Synthesis and Sampling</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Synthesis Techniques:</strong> Various synthesis techniques, such as subtractive, additive, and granular synthesis, allow for the creation of unique sounds from basic waveforms.</li>
  <li><strong>Sampling:</strong> Sampling involves recording and manipulating snippets of sound, which can be used creatively in music production. The evolution of sampling technology has led to innovative uses in genres like hip-hop and electronic music.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="impact-of-technology-on-music-production">Impact of Technology on Music Production</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> Technological advancements have democratized music production, making it accessible to a wider audience. Affordable software and hardware enable aspiring musicians to create professional-quality recordings from home studios.</li>
  <li><strong>Collaboration:</strong> Technology facilitates remote collaboration, allowing artists from different parts of the world to work together seamlessly.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="future-trends-in-sound-technology">Future Trends in Sound Technology</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Artificial Intelligence:</strong> AI is increasingly being used in music production, from generating compositions to mastering tracks. The potential for AI to assist and augment human creativity is a growing area of interest.</li>
  <li><strong>Virtual Reality and Immersive Audio:</strong> VR and immersive audio technologies are creating new ways to experience sound, with applications in gaming, virtual concerts, and interactive installations.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="conclusion-4">Conclusion</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Technological Influence:</strong> The exploration of sound and technology highlights the profound impact that technological advancements have had on the creation, manipulation, and perception of sound.</li>
  <li><strong>Continued Innovation:</strong> As technology continues to evolve, it will undoubtedly shape the future of sound in ways we can only begin to imagine.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="iv--sound-and-the-environment">IV : Sound and the Environment</h2>

<h3 id="introduction-to-sound-and-the-environment">Introduction to Sound and the Environment</h3>

<h4 id="overview-1">Overview</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Theme of the Week:</strong> This week’s lectures focus on the relationship between sound and the environment, exploring how natural and built environments influence and are influenced by sound.</li>
  <li><strong>Environmental Soundscapes:</strong> The discussion begins with an exploration of environmental soundscapes, emphasizing the importance of listening to and understanding the sounds of our surroundings.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="natural-soundscapes">Natural Soundscapes</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Biophony:</strong> The sounds produced by living organisms, such as birdsong, insect calls, and animal vocalizations, create a rich tapestry of natural soundscapes.</li>
  <li><strong>Geophony:</strong> Non-biological natural sounds, such as wind, rain, and ocean waves, contribute to the overall soundscape of an environment.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="human-impact-on-soundscapes">Human Impact on Soundscapes</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Anthropophony:</strong> Human activities, including urbanization, transportation, and industrial processes, significantly alter natural soundscapes, often leading to noise pollution.</li>
  <li><strong>Conservation Efforts:</strong> Efforts to preserve and restore natural soundscapes are discussed, highlighting the importance of protecting acoustic environments for both ecological and human well-being.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="acoustic-ecology">Acoustic Ecology</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Soundscape Ecology:</strong> The study of soundscape ecology examines the relationships between living organisms and their acoustic environment, providing insights into ecosystem health and biodiversity.</li>
  <li><strong>Field Recording:</strong> Field recording techniques are explored, emphasizing the role of sound artists and researchers in documenting and analyzing environmental soundscapes.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="sound-in-urban-environments">Sound in Urban Environments</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Urban Soundscapes:</strong> The unique challenges and opportunities of urban soundscapes are discussed, including the impact of architecture, transportation, and public spaces on the acoustic environment.</li>
  <li><strong>Noise Mitigation:</strong> Strategies for mitigating noise pollution in urban areas are explored, such as the use of green spaces, sound barriers, and innovative urban design.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="sound-and-climate-change">Sound and Climate Change</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Climate Change Impact:</strong> The impact of climate change on natural soundscapes is examined, with examples of how changing weather patterns and rising temperatures affect the sounds of different environments.</li>
  <li><strong>Raising Awareness:</strong> The role of sound in raising awareness about climate change is highlighted, with examples of sound art and installations that engage the public in environmental issues.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="conclusion-5">Conclusion</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Interconnectedness:</strong> The exploration of sound and the environment underscores the interconnectedness of natural and human-made soundscapes.</li>
  <li><strong>Sustainable Practices:</strong> Emphasizing the importance of sustainable practices, the discussion concludes with a call to action for preserving and enhancing the acoustic environments we inhabit.
    <h2 id="iv--sound-and-the-environment-1">IV : Sound and the Environment</h2>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="introduction-to-sound-and-the-environment-1">Introduction to Sound and the Environment</h3>

<h4 id="overview-2">Overview</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Theme of the Week:</strong> This week’s lectures focus on the relationship between sound and the environment, exploring how natural and built environments influence and are influenced by sound.</li>
  <li><strong>Environmental Soundscapes:</strong> The discussion begins with an exploration of environmental soundscapes, emphasizing the importance of listening to and understanding the sounds of our surroundings.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="natural-soundscapes-1">Natural Soundscapes</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Biophony:</strong> The sounds produced by living organisms, such as birdsong, insect calls, and animal vocalizations, create a rich tapestry of natural soundscapes.</li>
  <li><strong>Geophony:</strong> Non-biological natural sounds, such as wind, rain, and ocean waves, contribute to the overall soundscape of an environment.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="human-impact-on-soundscapes-1">Human Impact on Soundscapes</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Anthropophony:</strong> Human activities, including urbanization, transportation, and industrial processes, significantly alter natural soundscapes, often leading to noise pollution.</li>
  <li><strong>Conservation Efforts:</strong> Efforts to preserve and restore natural soundscapes are discussed, highlighting the importance of protecting acoustic environments for both ecological and human well-being.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="acoustic-ecology-1">Acoustic Ecology</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Soundscape Ecology:</strong> The study of soundscape ecology examines the relationships between living organisms and their acoustic environment, providing insights into ecosystem health and biodiversity.</li>
  <li><strong>Field Recording:</strong> Field recording techniques are explored, emphasizing the role of sound artists and researchers in documenting and analyzing environmental soundscapes.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="sound-in-urban-environments-1">Sound in Urban Environments</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Urban Soundscapes:</strong> The unique challenges and opportunities of urban soundscapes are discussed, including the impact of architecture, transportation, and public spaces on the acoustic environment.</li>
  <li><strong>Noise Mitigation:</strong> Strategies for mitigating noise pollution in urban areas are explored, such as the use of green spaces, sound barriers, and innovative urban design.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="sound-and-climate-change-1">Sound and Climate Change</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Climate Change Impact:</strong> The impact of climate change on natural soundscapes is examined, with examples of how changing weather patterns and rising temperatures affect the sounds of different environments.</li>
  <li><strong>Raising Awareness:</strong> The role of sound in raising awareness about climate change is highlighted, with examples of sound art and installations that engage the public in environmental issues.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="conclusion-6">Conclusion</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Interconnectedness:</strong> The exploration of sound and the environment underscores the interconnectedness of natural and human-made soundscapes.</li>
  <li><strong>Sustainable Practices:</strong> Emphasizing the importance of sustainable practices, the discussion concludes with a call to action for preserving and enhancing the acoustic environments we inhabit.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="v--sound-and-culture">V : Sound and Culture</h2>

<h3 id="introduction-to-sound-and-culture">Introduction to Sound and Culture</h3>

<h4 id="overview-3">Overview</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Theme of the Week:</strong> This week’s lectures focus on the relationship between sound and culture, exploring how sound shapes and is shaped by cultural practices and traditions.</li>
  <li><strong>Cultural Soundscapes:</strong> The discussion begins with an exploration of cultural soundscapes, emphasizing the diversity of sounds across different cultures and societies.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="traditional-music-and-rituals">Traditional Music and Rituals</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Cultural Significance:</strong> Traditional music and rituals play a vital role in cultural identity, with sound serving as a medium for storytelling, celebration, and spiritual practices.</li>
  <li><strong>Examples:</strong> Examples from various cultures are provided, such as the use of drums in African ceremonies, the chanting of mantras in Buddhist rituals, and the playing of didgeridoos in Aboriginal Australian traditions.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="sound-and-language">Sound and Language</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Phonetics and Linguistics:</strong> The study of phonetics and linguistics reveals the intricate relationship between sound and language, with different languages exhibiting unique phonetic characteristics.</li>
  <li><strong>Oral Traditions:</strong> Oral traditions, including storytelling, poetry, and song, are explored as vital components of cultural heritage, preserving history and knowledge through sound.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="popular-music-and-globalization">Popular Music and Globalization</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Cultural Exchange:</strong> The impact of globalization on popular music is discussed, highlighting the exchange of musical styles and influences across cultures.</li>
  <li><strong>Hybrid Genres:</strong> The emergence of hybrid genres, such as reggaeton, K-pop, and Afrobeat, illustrates the blending of cultural sounds in contemporary music.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="sound-in-media-and-entertainment">Sound in Media and Entertainment</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Film and Television:</strong> The role of sound in film and television is examined, with a focus on how sound design, music, and dialogue contribute to storytelling and audience engagement.</li>
  <li><strong>Video Games:</strong> The importance of sound in video games is highlighted, emphasizing the role of sound effects, music, and voice acting in creating immersive gaming experiences.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="sound-and-identity">Sound and Identity</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Personal and Collective Identity:</strong> The relationship between sound and identity is explored, with sound serving as a marker of personal and collective identity.</li>
  <li><strong>Examples:</strong> Examples include the use of national anthems, protest songs, and regional dialects to express and reinforce cultural identity.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="conclusion-7">Conclusion</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Cultural Significance:</strong> The exploration of sound and culture underscores the profound significance of sound in shaping cultural practices and identities.</li>
  <li><strong>Diverse Perspectives:</strong> Emphasizing the diversity of cultural soundscapes, the discussion concludes with a call to appreciate and preserve the rich tapestry of sounds that define our world.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Eman Safavi</name></author><category term="Sound" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The MOOC of Experiment with Sounds Charles Gaines: Transcribes manifestos into musical scores. Anna Halprin: Choreographic scores in modern dance. Beau Dick: Carves masks with their own songs and ceremonies. Brian Eno: Concept of “Discrete Music” in airports. Scott Lindroth: Works with The Garage &amp; Found Metal Ensemble. Christina Kubisch: Explores the sound of electromagnetic waves. Matthew Kenney: Integrates artistic talent and research, focusing on sonification and data visualization. Alvin Lucier: “I am sitting in a room” composition. Bernhard Leitner: Emphasizes sound as a constructive material for architecture. Shea Trahan: Explores resonant forms in architecture using sound vibrations on metal plates. Thomas Kusitzky: Researches auditory architecture in public spaces.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome To Jekyll copy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/07/welcome-to-jekyll-copy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome To Jekyll copy" /><published>2025-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/07/welcome-to-jekyll%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/07/welcome-to-jekyll-copy.html"><![CDATA[<p>#
layout: post
title:  “Temp Post”
date:   2025-01-08 17:09:53 +0100
categories: music, VCV rack
image: /assets/images/eman-portrait.png
#—</p>

<h2 id="this-is-a-temp-post">this is a temp post</h2>

<p>You’ll find this post in your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll serve</code>, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</p>

<p>Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP</code></p>

<p>Where <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR</code> is a four-digit number, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MONTH</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">DAY</code> are both two-digit numbers, and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MARKUP</code> is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.</p>

<p>Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">"Hi, </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">"</span>
<span class="k">end</span>
<span class="n">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">'Tom'</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="c1">#=&gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Check out the <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home">Jekyll docs</a> for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at <a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll’s GitHub repo</a>. If you have questions, you can ask them on <a href="https://talk.jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll Talk</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[# layout: post title: “Temp Post” date: 2025-01-08 17:09:53 +0100 categories: music, VCV rack image: /assets/images/eman-portrait.png #—]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Violet Bubbles – A December 2022 Snapshot</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/vcv%20rack/music/reflections/2022/12/13/Violet-Bubbles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Violet Bubbles – A December 2022 Snapshot" /><published>2022-12-13T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-12-13T11:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/vcv%20rack/music/reflections/2022/12/13/Violet%20Bubbles</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/vcv%20rack/music/reflections/2022/12/13/Violet-Bubbles.html"><![CDATA[<p>In <strong>December 2022</strong>, I found myself in a challenging space—life was intense, and the sounds I heard in my inner universe weren’t especially vivid or polished. Yet, as an artist, I decided to share what I was creating, even if it wasn’t “perfect.” After all, in a world full of polished YouTube performances, it’s easy to lose confidence. But I realized imperfection can be more honest and real, so here it is: my patch called <strong><em>Violet Bubbles</em></strong>.</p>

<h2 id="the-patch-violet-bubbles">The Patch: Violet Bubbles</h2>
<p>I built this patch in <strong>VCV Rack (free version)</strong>. It’s structured around:</p>
<ul>
  <li>A <strong>quantized sequence</strong> running through <strong>two oscillators</strong></li>
  <li>A <strong>simple drum machine</strong> with reflections that often appear before the actual sound, adding a surreal sense of motion</li>
  <li>A live-played <strong>bass part</strong> on a MIDI controller</li>
  <li>Delayed and modulated sounds layered in as the piece progresses</li>
  <li>The concept of starting with bit-crushed noise and distortion, then revealing the main sounds, and finally returning to noise at the end</li>
</ul>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/svXpRCQ70o0?si=5_r6_c4oKyPwn620" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<blockquote>
  <p>Download the patch here: <a href="https://patchstorage.com/violet-bubbles/">https://patchstorage.com/violet-bubbles/</a></p>
</blockquote>

<p>I called it <em>Violet Bubbles</em> because, in those moments, I pictured violet spheres floating around me; for a brief time, I felt like I was off the ground—my own little journey to the moon and back.</p>

<h2 id="a-one-take-performance">A One-Take Performance</h2>
<p>This recording was entirely spontaneous:</p>
<ul>
  <li>I realized late in the process I should film it, so I just grabbed my phone and did a single take.</li>
  <li>The <strong>guitar and vocal part</strong> you hear was mixed in during video editing, aiming to capture the raw creative momentum in the moment.</li>
</ul>

<p>It only took me a few hours to edit, and I hope the result communicates both the imperfections and the sincerity that drove me to share it. As I work through the flux of life, I’m learning that sometimes the most honest art emerges before we make it “perfect.” Enjoy exploring this patch—maybe it’ll spark a little journey of your own.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="VCV Rack" /><category term="Music" /><category term="Reflections" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In December 2022, I found myself in a challenging space—life was intense, and the sounds I heard in my inner universe weren’t especially vivid or polished. Yet, as an artist, I decided to share what I was creating, even if it wasn’t “perfect.” After all, in a world full of polished YouTube performances, it’s easy to lose confidence. But I realized imperfection can be more honest and real, so here it is: my patch called Violet Bubbles.]]></summary></entry></feed>